themeasuredmom.com 2019-06-12

# Disclosure - The Measured Mom

_This policy was last updated on May 11, 2018.  _

**About The Measured Mom**

Founded in 2013 and based in America, The Measured Mom is an independently operated blog run by me, Anna Geiger. This website shares education resources for parents, teachers, tutors, daycare providers, librarians, and more.

**Privacy Policy**

Your privacy is important. To better protect it, I provide this notice explaining my online information practices. This privacy policy governs your use of themeasuredmom.com including any content, functionality and services offered on or through themeasuredmom.com.

I reserve the right to change this policy at any time. Changes will be posted to this page. You are responsible for periodically visiting this privacy policy to check for changes.

**Parental Consent**

If you are under 16 years old, you should not be using this website, leaving blog comments, or subscribing to either of my newsletters without parental permission.

**Your Consent**

Please read this privacy policy carefully. By using the website, you accept and agree to be bound by this privacy policy. If you do not wish to agree, you must not access or use this website.

**How We Protect Your Information**

The Measured Mom uses standard security protocols and works only with reputable third-party vendors.

**How Information Is Collected**

  * If you subscribe to The Measured Mom newsletter
  * If you subscribe to the Teaching Every Reader newsletter
  * If you leave a comment on the blog
  * If you purchase a product through [The Measured Mom shop](https://www.themeasuredmom.com/shop/)
  * Through website cookies and log files
  * Through Google Analytics

We use the information you provide to deliver the requested product and/or service, to improve our overall performance, and to provide you with offers, promotions, and information.

**Subscriber Newsletters**

If you join The Measured Mom or Teaching Every Reader newsletter, you will be required to give your first name and email address. I require your email address to send you the emails, and I require a first name so that the emails will be more personal.

Your data is collected and then passed on to Convertkit, my email service provider.You can [read its privacy policy here](https://convertkit.com/privacy/).Tags are used within Convertkit to track your actions and page visits so that future emails can better meet your needs.

I send several emails per week. Occasionally I will send additional emails about special offers.

If you sign up for the newsletter and receive a subscriber freebie at the same time, I collect your information through a third party application called Leadpages. You can [read its privacy policy here.](https://www.leadpages.net/privacy)

Your email and name are never sold, rented, leased, or given away to a third party.

At the bottom of each newsletter you will find information about how to contact the sender, as well as a link to unsubscribe. You may unsubscribe at any time.

**Blog Comments**

When you leave a blog comment, your comment is public and visible. Your email address is never disclosed unless you include it in the main body of the comment. Your name and comment (as well as your URL, if you provide it), are visible to anyone who visits the comment section. Please avoid leaving any personal information in your comments.

Your details will remain in the database unless I remove it or you request to have it removed.

I reserve the right to remove or edit comments at my discretion. These may include comments containing profanity, harassment, threats, self-promotion, or spam.

**Shop Purchases**

Products in The Measured Mom Shop are sold through Woocommerce. Your name, email address, and country are required during the checkout process.  I am legally required to collect your physical address if you are a Wisconsin resident (I use this information to pay taxes on your purchase).

Payments are made through Paypal ([read its privacy policy here](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)) or Stripe ([read its privacy policy here](https://stripe.com/us/privacy)).

Information about your purchase is stored indefinitely. This way I can resend the files any time you request them. Only your name, email address and physical address (if required) is stored on my site.

You may also purchase my products on Teachers Pay Teachers. [Read its privacy policy here.](https://www.teacherspayteachers.com/Privacy-Policy)

I also sell other bloggers’ products via affiliate programs. Each program collects and retains its own data. I do not have access to the personal information that is collected by these affiliate programs.

**Cookies and Pixels**

This website uses a technology called “cookies” and server logs to collect information about how the site is used. Cookies are little pieces of code that I use to track your use of this site and provide the best possible experience for you.

Cookies may collect information including  the date and time of your visit, the pages viewed, time spent on the site, and your IP address. This site also reserves the right to use social media pixels which allow social media sites to track visitors to outside websites. This helps tailor the advertising messages you see when visiting those social media sites.

  * Amazon (for advertising)*
  * Facebook Pixel (for Facebook ad targeting)
  * Google Analytics (for tracking website traffic and user behavior)
  * Convertkit (for email tracking)
  * WP Affiliate (for tracking purchases made through affiliates)

If you wish to disable cookies, you can learn how to do that by visiting the websites of Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer, or that of a different browser.

*The Measured Mom is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide  a means for earning advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com. This doesn’t cost you an extra cent.

**Google Analytics**

The Measured Mom uses Google Analytics to track website performance and behavior. It provides information on pageviews, referral sources (such as another website or a social media site), your device (i.e. mobile or desktop), browsing actions, and other information that helps me adapt the content I write for this site.

Google Analytics collects anonymous information about your location, age, gender, IP address, and interests. I have no way to connect that information to you personally. Read about Google Analytics’ data retention policy [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7667196?hl=en&utm_id=ad).

**Links to Third Party Websites**

I include links to third party websites for your use and reference. I am not responsible for the privacy policies on these sites. Be aware that their privacy policies may be different than that of The Measured Mom.

**Advertisements**

Third party advertisements are used on this website. I currently run ads through Adthrive. Adthrive may use cookies or web beacons when they advertise on this site in order to show ads that would most interest you. The Measured Mom does not control Adthrive’s tracking technologies or how they may be used.

**Social Media**

The Measured Mom posts information on various social media platforms. The Measured Mom is not responsible for your privacy when you post on its social media channels.

**When I May Transfer Your Personal Data**

I will not transfer your personal data unless I am under legal obligation to do so.

**Contact**

If you would like your information to be removed from our systems, or have questions about this privacy policy, please email anna@themeasuredmom.com.
